Charlotte Asencio

CONTACT

252-903-1274

charlotte.e.asencio@gmail.com

charlotteasencio.com

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Social Work
Honors College
Belmont University, Nashville, TN

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

The Coding Bootcamp at UNC Charlotte

LANGUAGES

Fluent in Spanish

CONNECT





ABOUT ME

As a developer with a background in Social Work, I am especially interested in the way technology can improve the world and people's access to communication and services. I have experience working with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JavaScript frameworks including React and Angular, and Node.js.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Study Programmer I

Clinical Ink

June 2018-Present Winston-Salem, NC

- Design and Build electronic source documents for clinical trials according to protocol specifications.
- Program functionality and scoring into source documents utilizing JavaScript and some C# inside of Logical Ink Form Designer.
- Worked on the front-end for a proof of concept project for a new internal software initiative to improve internal tools that was used as a part of obtaining board approval of that initiative. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Angular
- Used VBA Macros to implement a change tracking system to a company wide
 Excel document in order to provide documentation of what changes were made,
 when they were made, and by which users.

PROJECTS

Pay It Forward

Coding Bootcamp at UNC Charlotte

- An example web app that allows nonprofit organizations to connect with interested volunteers.
- Includes user authentication utilizing firebase and differing role permissions. Allows users with an organization account to post volunteer opportunities and users with volunteer profiles to sign up for those opportunities.
- Technologies used: React, CSS, Firebase Database, Firebase Hosting

International Space Station Locator

- A JavaScript application built using Google Maps and Reverse Geocoder APIs along with the "Where the ISS At?" API to display a custom marker representing the current location of the ISS and the nearest address to that location.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Victim Services CoordinatorForsyth County District Attorney's Office

April 2016-May 2018 Winston-Salem, NC

Support Team Coordinator Safe Passage/ Camino Seguoro

Feb 2015-August 2015 Guatemala City, Guatemala